Good morning, good evening, good
afternoon. Welcome everyone to another
episode of S talk show. At your
pleasure, please play at 1.5 speed if
you are watching this offline because I
talk casually and slowly.
It's getting hot in California.
And today we are going to do random
randomish. So I'm a tech nerd. I'm a
computer nerd. I'm going to talk about
computer stuff. And meanwhile, like
yesterday,
we are going to have a sip of this room.
I'm a brick seller.
And George
uh George told me take it easy.
Uh you know, so I I'll take it easy.
Okay. So we just going to have like two
shots maybe.
Oh my god, my hand hurts. You see right
now? Why? Because you don't understand.
Okay. Like right here. Like right. Okay.
You can see uh here. Okay. The because I
type too much so I have injury like like
at the moment you know it hurts.
Uh I type so much.
I told the story before but I would say
for 10 years like now you know like you
have the Olympic record. Okay. Let me
switch to my screen so you can see.
Okay.
Okay. Now you can see today's topic. So
if you are here, say hi. I love to see
your comments. Okay. Am I alive? Let's
double check. Uh double check what does
video say? What does YouTube say? Stream
health and what whatever whatnot. Stream
settings whatnot. Uh current viewers
analytics stream settings. What is this?
Zero concurrent viewers. [laughter]
Okay, I think that's good. Okay. So, am
I actually um
I think I'm rolling. Okay. So, like it
right hurts right here. Okay. Because so
the story is that you know you have
Olympic record you know you have the
so-called Guinness record something like
that.
So they record you know the longest you
know the guy with the longest head head
uh you know biggest head you know
longest tallest guy whatever. and uh the
person who can do the most pushup and so
on, right? Guinness record. So if they
have a record who recorded, you know,
the guy who sits on the chair like what
I'm doing right now, sit sits on the
chair for the longest
on average for for a period uh 10 of 10
years. Okay, I would be in the top 100
in the world. Okay. I would say so that
that that period is 2010 to 2020.
You sit on on the chair the moment you
wake up you sit. Actually, you know,
speaking of records, they are crazy
people like monks or such that they
they they don't sit all day. I mean I
mean they they sit or or assume a
position all their life like for years
for 10 years. So I read there's a story
uh an Indian uh monk something who you
know hold his hands up like for like for
all his life or stand or stand for for
for his life. So his limbs became
um they became um
how do you say they they they they got
deformed. Okay. It changes you know the
the the bone it changes your body. So
anyway, there are such extremes. So I'm
not that extreme, but I would say I I
you know, I would be in the record for
the guy who sit in front of the computer
in a span of 10 years, the longest.
Okay. Top 100, I would say. So here's a
drink.
By the way, I was listening to music.
Fantastic music. So, let me show you
music blog showing browser. So, you can
go to that's on kasali.org.
Search a h my name. Music blog, you'll
find it. So there is this song I
discovered about two or three years ago.
Amazing.
He'll give us what we really need by
this holy name of Mary Coral family kind
of um
uh kind of religious song. Okay. I I I
I'm not sure how do you classify but so
this is one of the great song.
um you know I don't want to play it
because then Google is going to flag my
video. So that's a great song and
another great song. So okay so these are
gospels I suppose they are like I'm not
too sure but maybe they are classified
as gospels. I I'm not sure but another
one is great I learned from Lunaras from
our forum from Kasad Discord Lunaras. So
there is there's this song kind of uh
heavy metal. So Judah's priest. Okay.
Dreamer, deceiver, and uh deceiver.
Wait. Dreamer, deceiver, and de
deceiver. Dreamer, deceiver, and
deceiver. Uh did I get the name right?
Yeah. Okay, that's I suppose that's the
name. Anyway, so that's a great music.
Okay.
[sighs and gasps]
So that's that um that you know some
music so you can enjoy but uh today I'm
going to do some coding.
I'm going to do some coding. Okay. See
uh nobody's here.
should have at least one. Am I actually
live? So, let me double check. Okay, so
stream settings, analytics, concurrent
viewers, zero, chat rate zero, views
zero, average duration.
Uh,
but is it like actually going?
Cheers.
Okay, I believe it is. So you see this
button live for seven minutes. Okay, so
we start to going to code. Okay, let me
show you. Let's close that. Showing
browser Emacs power. Okay, Emacs the the
superb Emacs power extreme
uh and uh uh my setup. Okay, so you can
you know it's uh kasfly keys. It's free
online. You can get it kasfly keys.
Okay, just search for it, you'll find
it. I I have tens of videos about it.
Okay, so so let me mention one of the
thing I did in the past month is
cascading stylesheet grid layout. Okay,
fantastic. [snorts] Now this is a
innovation you know because the this
grid layout allows you to
create layouts like magazine layout,
newspaper layout and so on without you
ever have to specify one length. Okay.
So because so so this this is a computer
language designed to specify layout in a
very high level and ab abstract level
and you don't even need to specify one
single length. Okay, it's this uh grid
layout which came out about 10 years
ago. So I finally wrote a tutorial. I
think I talked about it a month ago. So
you know so check out my tutorial. Okay,
so you got great layout. So you check
out visual CSS, you know, go to
kasali.info,
all my programming language tutorials.
That's what I do for my life, basically
writing and writing.
And you go down, you'll see the
cascading stylesheet section. Now they
have official logo I talked about
yesterday also. And so you got you get
to the visual CSS. Then you go to the
layout and uh uh section. Layout is the
most useful. It's actually the most
useful part of CSS. But it so happens is
also the most difficult to understand
part of CSS. Okay. So you go to layout.
So there's flexbox. It's also new 10
years ago or about uh 15 years ago. Uh
10 to 15. So great layout. So there.
Okay. So you can check it out. my
tutorial.
Okay, that's one thing. Um, next, uh, I
wanted to do something, uh, some some
Okay, so this would be demo of Emacs
power, Emacs micro power. So you can
see, so if we go to go back to let's say
uh, CSS grid layout, you know, you go
back to visual CSS my web page. Um then
you go to there's my blog webdev blog
tremendous work in the past few months.
So and so webdev blog then you go to the
archive section. So that's my archive of
the past uh blogs starting in 2010. In
fact, it's before 2010, but 2010 January
is is when I started to have a dedicated
blog dedicated to webdev.
Before that, before 2010, it was part of
my other blog called periodic dosage.
Okay. So, but 2010 is when I moved, you
know, this into a dedicated
blog just for webdev. So you can see the
first article. So you see you you know
when you blog when you are a blogger or
writer for a long time you can look at
the past for example this 2010 uh you
kind of have a mini record of history.
So you can see what I what was I talking
about 2010 January 13th more juice from
the Google exit China threat [snorts]
from the Wall Street Journal. Okay. So,
so now you know 2010 is when Google
there's a splash of news about how
Google is exiting China. Google warns of
China exit over hacking.
Cheers.
So now I got three concurrent viewers.
Who are you? Say hi. Okay. Sispa,
good night. Feeling better. Um you know
you see yesterday I was drinking and you
guys can see me you know I cried you
know I got tears but actually but you
guys don't know so you see that's kind
you know that situation me
that's kind of chronic okay so it's kind
of I would say it's so you would you
know the according to the white man the
western people it's a it's it's a mental
it's you know what you know the way what
they would call um is
[laughter]
they they call that um
what's the name um poststress
trauma something like that okay that's
what they call
trauma syndrome something like that
Okay.
Yeah. Post-traumatic stress disorder,
PTSD.
So, for example, in the past, you know,
since the rise of social justice
warriors, [ __ ] scums of the deep
state. They they are kind of pawns. A
lot of them are young people and women,
you know, beginning with women because
women, the females are the most easy to
manip manipulate by the big powers by
men basically by men at the top. They
manipulate women. So women, so for the
past 10 years, you know, like beginning
2016, let's say 2016 to
uh 2026,
well, let's say 2016 to 2020, okay?
Especially that period you have what I
would call social justice warrior
period. Okay, that's a period when you
know people talk about feminism,
patriarchy.
They are angry and they hate the white
men, you know, things like that. You
guys probably you know some of you know
that. Okay.
And then eventually the powering of the
trans so-called. Okay. So anyway, so
that that's a period a lot of women, you
know, they talk about rape all the time.
That's like a white man's obsession.
They talk about rape all the time.
So these women, many of them will talk
about the post-traumatic stress
disorder, you know, because uh they say,
"Oh, every woman is raped." Something
something like that. Okay? Like like one
in every three something.
H uh so oh god it's you know it's going
to be sad if I talk about this anyway
let me let me briefly describe so you
got this so you got this post-traumatic
stress disorder in fact that's what I
have okay
uh these people you know this this these
pe you know well you don't know okay so
like even if you watched me live stream
I've been live streaming for five years
but but But but but what you don't know
is that usually live stream is it shows
a part of yourself like whatever person
you are watching only part of it like
there are other parts you don't you'll
never see even though you watch the guy
you think you know the guy so much you
know even though the guy is honest but
but still live streaming you know
whoever you know the host me
always there's always a kind of a
conscious choice like what you want to
show and what you do not want to show.
Okay. So, so I have this post-traumatic
stress disorder kind kind of. Yeah, I'm
sure. But um but you wouldn't know like
you don't know. Okay. So,
so you know yesterday I was drinking and
I feel sad and but that's uh that's kind
of that's that's my PT ptsd
okay but exactly what is a trauma I have
you don't you don't know okay that's
because of my dad
uh oh god so I feel the pain again here
because you see the let me talk about
keyboards okay I'm just going to talk
about random okay so as you know if you
are new here you don't know me so I'm
well known for my keyboard blogs like
some people consider me
you know I'm I'm kind of expert for
especially on ergonomic keyboard okay so
this keyboard blog there are 10,000
articles in it ergonomic keyboards uh do
it yourself I talked about many times
Okay.
So,
so yeah. So, I was typing so much. I got
hand pen right here. Um, so yeah, what I
was going to say is that you see the
hand pen is actually part of the uh
repetitive repetitive strain injury. So,
if you want um so let me go there. So
all about typing tips uh all about um
proper sitting position health issues
you know ergonomics if you have hand pen
a lot of programmers do uh then so
there's then there's a typing issues
touch typing what is touch typing
uh how to touch type does touch typing
cause repetitive strain injury you know
things like that or lots of articles
okay
So actually part of it you know has to
do with psychology.
So recent month I don't feel so good. So
that I think that's a part of reason I'm
feeling pain right now here even though
because I'm not actually I didn't type
that much.
Okay. So lots of digressions. Okay. So
let me go back. I want to I want to do
this um webdev my blog. Okay. So I have
a blog you know I have so many blogs 10
more than 10. So so this blog is about
webdev JavaScript HTML CSS and
periodically I make them into a archive
because otherwise you know this page is
going to be too long spanning 10 years.
So you go to the archive page and uh go
to the archive page. So each block entry
has a year date. So this one is 2025
January. That's the beginning. Okay. So
this this one covers 2025 January to
December. Basically the entire 2025
year. Okay. Go back and here's 2024.
Uh so but what I want to do is I want to
make the
period like from and to more explicit.
So for example, let me show you. Okay,
again I'm just doing random chat. Okay,
random chat and whatever whatever. So
delete that. So copy the URL.
Uh open it showing browser. So we are
opening the page in Emacs right here. So
you can see. So what I want for example
this block 2025 to 2021 I want it to
rename it to be like
uh 12. Okay. Showing browser. So I
wanted to rename it like that.
I didn't do that before because I
thought so this is about design of the
titles. I didn't do that before because
I thought
when you have two dates that's kind of
more confusing because when you have one
date it's simpler because once you know
so so you so each of these year is year
and month is a starting date. So for
example 2018 August that's a beginning
date. So this page would contain if you
go all the way to the bottom 2018 June
to to um 2000 August. Okay. You see? So
so but you got um you got
inconsistencies,
you know, like one after a while you
forgot should the date be the beginning
date or should it be the ending date. So
I apparently I got inconsistent here.
So that's why I thought you know let's
just make the period full like from and
to um
so apparently I have inconsistencies
here. So you see 2018 that's the ending
ending month. Now let's see uh 20178.
Okay that's the ending.
Let's see uh 2017 August. No, that's um
so you see that's a problem. If you have
the from and two year, that would be
much more clear. Okay, so what I want to
do is fix that.
So this is 2024
January, you see? So that's a beginning
date, but this page is actually ends on
December.
Okay, so I need to fix that.
Uh, talking about keyboards, I recently
bought my very first split keyboard, the
Kong V4. Fantastic Kong V4.
So, I have a blog about Kong keyboard.
Of course, Kong. So, this guy the I
believe they are Russian. Uh, that's the
Russian do-ityourself. So, Kong V. So,
but basically I stopped blogging about
keyboards a few years ago because
why? Because uh
open a new link. Okay, so that's a
chrome keyboard.
The reason I stopped blogging about
keyboard is because after 10 years it
become, you know, it's not too
important. I mean the uh all the
ergonomic ones like their design their
shape is basically all has been done.
Okay. So it's you know it's all been
done. So the keyboard scene the
ergonomic keyboard scene beginning it
began around 2012. Okay. the entire
ergonomic keyboard
um community and do it yourself
beginning about 2012 that's also when
the 3D printing became very popular it's
you know so it's a result of technology
so you got this but you know but after
10 years all the variations all the
possible uh design it kind of all
explored so you some of them is very
weird for example You got the, you know,
you got this thumb hole. You you you
poke your thumb inside, you know. Very
funny. I haven't tried it. This one is
from Japan.
So anyway, so I kind of stopped, you
know, naturally. Um and also when you
get to you know basically you know you
stop the topic uh because it's you know
keyboard that's you know that's very
popular you know but also um
computer programming and mathematics
mathematics is far more important and
deeper okay so I haven't done much about
keyboard blogs uh I haven't blogged much
about keyboards for the past few
kind of stopped and I think it's natural
because you you know anyway
uh anyway so so you are talking about
Kong version 4 so I don't know what is a
chrome version 4 so let's have a look
okay so do they still have their uh page
let's see so you see kong keyboard they
are from 2019
and here is a go programming language
logo f mascot fantastic Funny. I love
it. Keycaps. Okay, so let's go to their
homepage. In fact, the guy the guy who
created Kong keyboard, he mentioned me
on his blog
because I made fun of the keyboard
because I think it's silly to have a
keyboard, you know, like um
like the drone keyboard. Okay. So, the
drone keyboard mentioned me uh
somewhere. Okay. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> because the drone keyboard you see they
got the like a single key at the corner
right you know very kind of silly anyway
I don't I don't like this minimalist you
know like 30 keys 40 keys I don't like
these keyboards
anyway so uh so let's see what they uh
so what they got keyboard uh
so is this still the page version 4 um
yeah it is okay. Version four, hard
swappable. Okay.
Magnify.
Okay. So,
you have page about do yourself
keyboard? Yes. Okay. So, [snorts] have
you watched Breaking Bad Kasawa?
If yes, what do you think about it? No,
I have not watched Breaking Bad. I don't
watch TV. So, you see since 2000,
year 2000,
I stopped watching any TV. So, back then
you don't have internet yet. Okay.
Oh, so Breaking Back, Breaking Bad is a
uh TV series, you know. So you know so
in 2000 year 2000 you don't have
you don't have YouTube yet you don't
have these you know online videos
but back then what you watch is TV vast
majority of people you watch TV like
today you got Netflix you know you
zoomers
you know the zoomer generation you were
like 10 years old or maybe teen right
you watch Netflix you watch whatever I
don't even know you know YouTube Netflix
but in 2000 year 2000 there's no such
thing what people watch is TV okay TV is
like today's Netflix and whatever you
got TV or cable and channel and stuff
okay but I stopped I decided I stop
watch TV I don't want watch any TV at
all so in 2000 year 2000 I stopped watch
any TV
And so back then if you tell that to
people that's like shocking. Oh my god
this guy watched stopwatch t TV you know
the you know there's some admiration you
know something like that
because it's unusual. So you know I
don't watch TV because they are
you know they they they they kind of
wash your brain. Okay they they they
wash your brain.
So, let me have another shot
of rum.
Okay.
Cheap. So, this this huge bottle from
Costco, the American elite, middle class
elite, Costco.
Uh they are uh so this huge bottle is
$16. Okay.
So usually that'll last me two months
maybe or these days if I drink fast one
month.
So anyway, I don't watch TV, but
in two in year 2000, but I do watch
YouTube because YouTube is fantastic.
It's video made by people like you and
me. There's no corporate. You know, the
reason I don't like TV, they wash your
brain because they become, you know, the
American capitalism
is part of it. they they became just
like
uh
shallow you know shallow brainless you
know that that's what TV became I mean
that's what TV are shallow and brainless
and uh
so you have to understand when TV got
invented
that's a technological breakthrough just
like internet and today just like AI so
it's a so it's the first time you know
for example radio when radio was created
invented or when TV broadcasting was
invented. It's the first time the
communication technology breakthrough.
It's the first time when you can
communicate to a lot of people like
millions of people in one shot. That's
TV, okay? Radio and TV.
But that's, you know, that's before I
was born. So that's, you know, before my
generation. But
but then you know anyway today we got
internet. So in year 2000 I stopped
watching TV because they because what
they are is then then okay then TV
became like a tool of the uh
brainwashing by the powerful by the
powerful organization deep state. They
control your thought
in a way. Okay. in a way. Um,
and movie is kind of the same Hollywood
movies because when you know like almost
almost all of us especially Americans
you know we grew up watching movies
Hollywood you know they are superheroes
or wars or whatever science fiction uh
Star Wars fantastical you know but
actually they they they they
kind of wash your brain. Okay.
Even though even though um unintentional
because for example Star Wars very
innocent Star Wars or Star Trek although
you know in in on one hand you learned
um concept of
science fantasy such as teleportation
or war you know spaceships space travel
[snorts] but however your idea about
space is totally um fake. You know the
those in Star Wars and Star Trek uh
because they
because ultimately
when they create movies such as Star
Wars and Star Trek they want to attract
you, you know, you want to be excited.
Oh, you know shooting and you know
lasers you killing and you know that
what excites you makes you want to watch
it.
But that is also
um the reason it's not true you know you
are just you know you are just um buying
into fantasies you know that's it's
nothing like that space you know
spaceships you know it's not nothing
like that so so so even though they are
fun to watch they are innocent Star Wars
and Star Trek for example
but they do even that they they they uh
wash your brain Okay.
So anyway, I don't watch, you know, TV,
but today so but I watch YouTube. I
watch internet because it's just people.
There's no commercial. There's no but
starting around 2010 or later, you know,
YouTube became YouTube just became TV.
So this is a important message to you
guys, okay? It's [snorts] it's kind of
how society
run some you know something like that
you you see YouTube today is basically
became TV
you know you go to YouTube even if you
watch keyboard reviews you know you go
to YouTube you you watch keyboard
reviews right by by average people not
by big corporate entities you know like
l
Uh let's see Linus
Tech okay tech tips something like that
you know that guy you know he he began
as a you know a simple guy just like me
right but then today so there are like
thousand tens of thousands keyboard
reviews or computer reviews iPad reviews
you know uh GPU graphics card reviews
right but they became like they behave
just like corporations now since about
uh 2010,
you know, like when you start to watch
their video, they got a logo flying by.
They got, you know, music logo
fake. Okay, it's like a [ __ ] crap.
It's a [ __ ] fake. That's what this,
you know, these people became. That's
how, you know, money.
So, so what I'm saying is that you know
I stopped watching TV because it you
know it's corporate fake news basically
shallow brainless fake news and wash
wash your brain
but I like YouTube because it's made by
people but after 10 years YouTube is
basically became TV you know like and a
good example is the Linux tech tip tips
you know like he he's a normal average
guy and he just he became you know he
became just fake. He's just just all
fake and he's rich. He's fairly rich you
know several millions.
So that's a situation. Okay. And he you
know he then he branched into like so
many channels and whatnot. [ __ ]
and and like and and shallow like
brainless like every every his video
like like these days he he hire people
you know these are his staffs or
whatever but you look at the thumbnails
like each one is like the [ __ ]
[ __ ] you know insulting brainless
[ __ ] you know with this dramatic face oh
you know like and clickbait you know why
the fastest memory isn't in you
something why satellite Internet doesn't
suck, you know. [ __ ] this [ __ ]
[ __ ] They all became
well that's what you know. So so you see
that's a situation that's
so in a sense that's not you know so you
can't just blame this guy. It's not
particular to this guy Lena's guy. It's
how human behaves when there is money
you know like before YouTube is not like
TV but now it became even by each person
because there's money that's you know
that's how you attract people that's how
people follow you know people want you
know people naturally gravitate towards
drama and clickbait that's how you
became popular so in a way you learned
about
the human you know like like what what
what it means to be human. So you can't
so so maybe it's not the giant
corporations
are inherently evil but part of it is
because that's what human want you know
that's like how dumbs we are okay
something something like that
so so today for example I I look at
these uh Linux tech tips it's insulting
I don't watch I don't watch any of his
video. I find it very offensive.
So back to your question. Um so you are
saying there is a TV drama JavaScript is
disabled. Okay. So, let's enable it so
that Google or whoever this domain, they
can know where you came from, what you
[laughter]
what you are.
Breaking Bad. So, that's a TV series.
Uh, okay. Breaking Bad. I never heard of
it. So, what is it about? So, let's see.
Wikipedia. Breaking Bad.
It's American neestern crime drama.
Okay. I don't watch that much television
series created by this guy for AMC.
By the way, I heard AMC is owned by
China.
[laughter]
That's a you know that's a drama.
AMC is owned by China. Something like
that. Is it is it ownership AMC Global
Media? Okay, let's see. AMC, Global
Media, uh,
key people, product, brands. Uh, okay.
I'm somewhat drunk
right now. I'm I would say 30%. Okay.
When you are drunk, you can't think.
Okay. So, actually, I'm not doing
anything. So, I'm just like,
okay. So, I don't know what I'm doing.
So AMC TV channel. Okay. So anyway,
Breaking Bad.
So created by this guy Vince Gilligan.
Vince Gilligan. So today I'm um you know
when I look at these people
usually
by default I feel negative about them
and then I have to check who they are.
Okay. where they came from.
Uh, okay. I'm talking um
I don't know. Okay. So, I'm in a right
now my brain is functioning at 50%
capacity
because
the alcohol damages your
capacity of thinking. Okay.
But anyway, Breaking Bad. So, what is it
about? So by this guy set and filmed in
abacisk,
New Mexico that was Mexico but taken
over by USA about like 100 years ago or
something. The series follows water
white, a guy, okay, a white guy
apparently, water white and
overqualified high school chemistry
teacher
who after being diagnosed with stage
three learn cancer. Okay, he's about to
die. Begins producing and selling meta
femotamine. Okay. A drug that zombie
drug something like that with former
student Jesse Pinkman to secure his
family's financial future. So you got
this overqualified so very smart
chemistry teacher but he's got cancer
and he start to sell drugs to enrich his
family something like that. Okay.
So, the series also stars, you know,
Anna Gun. So, is she pretty? No.
[laughter]
That's what I care about. Uh, Anna Gun,
Ding Morris, whoever [ __ ] is that? I
don't know. Betsy Brandt, Betsy Brandt,
whoever that is. 53. Oh, Jesus.
Anyways, so starring these guys. So,
what So, what is it? So, it's a Okay, so
it's a television series about this
uh about this chemistry teacher who's
got learn cancer
smoking too much maybe [laughter]
like me, but I quit.
Okay. So, and he's starting to sell
drugs, okay, to cope. Okay. Breaking
Back premiered on AMC on 2008. So, okay.
So, it's not, you know, it's not it's
pretty old. Uh, and concluded on 2013.
Oh, okay. So, it's a old series you are
talking about.
Uh,
so there's a question. Why do you say
recycling is a scam? Because it is. You
know, I live in California, so I always
believed in recycling very much just
like every other nerds like I I would
first about, you know, oh, which kind of
paper would you know, this go to? Oh, I
I have to um take apart whatever device
and put metals in this bin or you know,
you know, recycling.
And then I turned out then you then you
start to read you know you look around
you recycling is like a big scam. Okay.
They don't they don't recycle. They send
your [ __ ] they they they they send the
[ __ ] to China. Okay. [laughter]
Like all the garbage to China to you
know to for them to process it. But five
years ago or 10 years ago, China refused
it, you know, because China became
powerful. They they don't want to, you
know, process the recycle [ __ ] anymore.
Uh basically it's is garbage. Okay. So
recycle. So let me let me just give you
the simple version. Recycle. For
example, let's limit to talk about
recycling
bottles, you know, Coca-Cola, you know,
plastic bottles or tin cans. You know,
the only thing you
really work for recycle is the tin can
like the metal, you know, can that can
recycle. Okay.
uh for plastic bottles and uh so wait
I'm kind of drunk so I can't think
clearly but anyway so
so what I can say for sure is that the
the metal tin cans those you can recycle
very well okay works but for uh plastic
bottles and glass
um
glass You can also recycle. Okay.
Anyway, I can't think clearly now
because I'm kind of drunk. So, class, I
think you can kind of recycle, but the
plastic bottle,
not really. Okay. They just end up in in
landfield, you know. They they they end
up in Philippines, you know. They they
end up in the ocean. It's basically the
whole thing is just scam. It's a major
scam. So who who created the recycle
idea the movement you know so it tells
the consumers like me like a nerd you
know like oh we need to recycle because
we can help the earth who created it
that's because that's created by the
chemistry the plastic
corporations mega corporations they
created so that
you know so they are very evil okay very
evil
Uh, [sighs] okay.
So, there's a question. Why do I use UHK
instead of Kinesis? Um,
well, I talked about that many times.
So, you know, it's not I because I only
have one desktop. Okay. So, I can only
use one keyboard at a time.
So, if I use UHK, you know, right now
I'm using Autoimate Hacking Keyboard.
Then people will say, "Oh, why are you
using that? Why why did you know did you
stop? Did you not like the Clintis or
did you not like the glove at?" Okay.
So if I use glove 80 then people will
question oh did you not like cleans this
you know because I only got one key you
know one
uh desktop
and I can't be bothered to like oh I
need to switch my keyboard every month
so that so that people can see I'm using
variety of keyboard okay
I just happen you know so so right now
I'm using this keyboard you know it
takes time to switch because every time
you switch you need to change all your
habit. you need to change for example um
so I can show you for um
auto hard key so I need to change my
auto hard key settings you know you got
few things to change like when you
change operating system you got you know
it's some work so
okay so that's why I'm just using this
right now so but that does not mean this
is the best. Uh this is actually kind of
expensive. So you just read my keyboard
um
blog. Okay. So for example, I can
recommend I talked about this many times
in my past videos. I have like over few
hundred videos on keyboards. So I like I
recommend glove 80
kinesis 360 also but
not so much the Kinesis advantage too
the old one but it's $100 cheaper. Okay
Mron not so much because it's kind of a
lot more you pay 100 or two more
uh and the advantage is not too much.
Okay. So, I recommend Glove 80, Kinesis
360,
and I recommend this one. I never used
it though, but I kind of I I think I can
recommend it. Okay. Uh, [clears throat]
Kinesis Mwave
and Expose. I always recommend, you
know, this is very cheap, too. $100 or
more or few more. Okay. Kinesis Expose
Night very much Apple Maker. I never uh
actually used it, but I think it's
probably very good and cheap. You know,
it's $80 or something.
How much is it now? So, let's see. Uh
you see, because this today you got lots
of cheap keyboard on Amazon. Okay.
Currently, not available instead.
Okay. So, Apple Maker. So you you see so
you got um then you ultimate hacking
keyboard 80 I can recommend well
actually so it's fairly expensive you
know
anyway I'm drunk and uh so I haven't
done this so let me do this okay I need
to do this um
why do you use uh K instead of kinesis
okay Uh I didn't see any mention of
reason on your website about it but
think you've said ortholinear and
concave is better. Okay. Yeah. You know
so the reason so you see the ultimate
hacking keyboard is not orolinear
meaning that you know so if you can
uh actually maybe I should stop because
I've been talking for long. So you can
see the keyboard is not authorinear.
That means you see the vertical
column of the keys is not straight.
Okay. So or linear means it's like like
a grid. It's all straight but this is
not.
So the so ortholinear is better. Okay.
It's better for sure but not much. Okay.
So like I said before, the most
important thing for ergonomic keyboard
is first of all the key switch. Okay,
the key switch and and tenting. Okay,
like you want the like you don't want
flat like that. You want some kind of
tenting.
Okay, so like you know like 30° is good
like like what I have.
So you want the the most important is a
key switch. You want light and linear.
Okay? And you want some tenting and you
want it split apart. You don't want like
you know you don't want connected one
piece you know you don't want you know
together. So these three things are the
most important and I talk I mentioned it
I mentioned this a thousand times. Okay.
[snorts] So that's the most important
for my 10 years experience.
Now [snorts] about the ortholine linear
that's not too important. Okay, turns
out that's not too important.
So anyway, did I write about it? You
know, it's hard to say because um you
know because so for example, if you go
to my keyboard blog, search for
ortholinear. Did I talk about it?
Orthodox keyboard? No, that's another
that's a keyboard. Okay, so let's see.
uh
keyboard layout stacker or linear it
okay it talks about uh several different
type of layout so you see orolinear is
like that you see so you can see and uh
or linear that's another one the most
the original do-ityourself the erodox
and expose aolinear u well it's author
So linear but with a twist. So it also
um has an angle.
So anyway, so and then you have
symmetric inward stagger. So for
example, you got this one from Japan.
Anyway, so
okay. So I'm not So I Let me go back. So
I want to do this. Okay. So close my
keyboard. That's enough about keyboard.
Let's let me do this. Okay. So,
so what I want to do is um so if you
show this in browser, look at this 2024
January.
Um
Patel
Patalos. Hi, my name is Pa Sanos.
[laughter]
I think he's a great guy, you know. I
I'm too old to watch other people's
videos. So, I don't
and also I'm a loner type of guy. So, my
personality is such that I don't I
haven't really been like following other
people's blog or other you know watch
other people's video rarely.
I do watch sometimes like professor you
know some some some video by some
professor one shot like you know if I
find it you know it's like some topic I
do watch but I almost never follow any
other bloggers or YouTubers in a regular
way so I don't like do that okay so the
the
potos
that guy is kind of popular, you know,
among the Emacs community. So, people
have mentioned him. I So, I watched, you
know, I I watched a couple of his video.
I think he's very smart. Okay. And so,
that's that's what I think. He he he's
kind of a philosophical kind of guy. So,
he's I think his mindset is kind of
similar to me. Okay. His personality
kind of similar.
Okay. So that's what I think of him.
Okay. So what what else you guys are
saying? So this thinking of getting the
NIA M 512 that's my track ball you are
use uh looking at. That's fantastic. Oh
you guys are not seeing my uh pages web
blog. Okay. So let me forgot to show it.
[ __ ]
Um I'm drunk.
Okay. Okay. So, I think I that's it for
today. Um,
so have I watched Breaking Bad? No. So,
I have not watched Breaking Bad. So,
what is [laughter]
what is this about? So, let's see. uh a
chemistry teacher diagnosed with
inoperable lung cancer turned to
manufacturing and selling meta
fetam with a former student to secure
his family's future. Okay, but what is
the point like what what is the like why
is this interesting or something?
Oh, so it's highly rated. So I must be
must be fun to watch. Uh so what is this
uh symbol mean?
Let's see.
Oh my god, look at this website. 382
[snorts]
JavaScript blocked and it's keep it's
increasing.
So [laughter] every minute also it keeps
loading a new JavaScript. You see now
amazing this website you know by the way
you guys may not know this IMDb
this IMDb was originally from 1980s
1990s it was originally a news group
collection news group so you guys don't
know what's a news group news group is
basically a forum like like a online
forum by people okay it's like a chat
room like it's kind of like today's
discord except it's not instantaneous
okay like you can go there you know like
forum you post and it goes there then
tomorrow you check back who's answer you
know who answered it okay so it's a
online discussion forum
news group that's what I'm talking about
okay so news group back then in 1980s
1990s there's a discussion about I think
it's named FAQ.mov
something you know like recov
recreational
movies so it belongs to one of the
community of recreation
and movies so basically what people do
is that people you know you watch movies
like people put all sort of information
oh by the way this movie the the stars
of this movie are this this this
director ctor is this guy is made in
this year and so on. you know a kind of
data all kind of data about the movie
and what people think about movie the
commentary the the short summary of the
movie
okay people wrote it okay not not the
corporation like today you know today
you
you know you can get you know the who
you know the director what year you know
where does it came from okay people made
it before 40 years ago like us like you
you just know one movie another people
know about another movie you know you go
there and post it that's how the the the
info get collected then someone pence
take taking the collect all the
information and and try to gather them
into a coherent database okay so that's
when that's that's why you can see you
know in this year what are movies made
in this year you have like all you can
list them you can search it you know so
this movie star, you know what kind of
movie he made, you know, so there's a
list. So, so people made it. Okay. So,
this is like in the 1980s
and 1990s called um
recreational like movies something like
in news group.
So that is so that's 1980s and 1990s.
Okay, that is the origin of the IMDb.
Amazon bought it for somehow. Okay, you
see this this movies FAQ in you know in
the news group made by people. It's not
I don't think it's owned by any any
particular person but anyway somehow
Amazon grabbed it. Amazon, the
corporation, they grabbed it and they
made it, you know, and they created the
website imdb.com.
So, you know, you can, you know, you can
probably read about it on Wikipedia.
Okay. So, you can see IMDb. Let's see
Wikipedia. Okay.
So formerly known as the internet movie
database is an online database of
information related to films,
television, podcast, video games and so
on. Before it was just movies, okay?
Then later on they added video games and
other [ __ ] and podcast. Okay, including
cast production, trivia and so on. The
database contains some 25 million stuff.
Okay, features. Okay, let's see history.
Uh, okay. I hope the history IMDb began
as a fan operated movie database on the
Usenet group. Okay, that's what I'm
talking about. Rec.
Okay, that's exactly in the 1990 and
moved to the worldwide web www.system
in 1993.
free website INDB originated from the
personal film database. Okay. Right. So
this core nitam had maintained as a
hobby since 1987.
Nitam who worked as a engineer at Hulip
Packard. Okay. Had been uh recording
details of every film he watched since
his teenage years. Yeah. That's like us
nuts.
So in 1980s he joins the Usenet group.
Okay. So when did Amazon bought it?
[sighs and gasps]
Okay. In 1993 the database moved onto
the fledgling worldwide web under the
name Cardiff Internet Movie Database.
The database resided on the servers of
the computer science department of
Cardiff University.
Okay, it's quite a long history but
eventually you see an internet
independent company in 1996 IMDb was
incorporated in the United Kingdom
becoming the internet movie database
limited. Okay. So it became so its
founder no co uh co nitam ham still the
guy. So he became the owner. So he he
made a company
gen general revenue for site operations
was generated through advertising. Okay.
Then Amazon subsidiary. Okay. So 1998
Amazon bought it.
Okay. That's a story. Okay. So I think
that's it. [sighs and gasps] AMDB suck.
Why does it suck?
OMDb. Okay. TMDB. No, I do I don't know
about them. I don't know check them
often.
Uh, okay. Uh, let's see what else. I
think that's it for today.
Have you used conad keyboard software
for non QMK? No, I have not. I don't
know what that is.
any tips on how to make how to take care
of hands and fingers? Uh, yes.
But now I'm like too tired to tell you.
Um,
you have to read my website. I'm too
tired.
I have a lot of finger pen saw after
many years of programming. Okay. And
what do you think about uh that guy
knows reasons? Okay. Did I miss
anything?
Breaking Bad. Okay. No, I haven't
watched Breaking Bad. How is the Nia
track ball? That's fantastic. Okay. I
highly recom I do recommend it.
Okay. Bye guys.
[sighs]
I'm going to have dinner.